allafrica.com 2009-06-19

# allAfrica.com: Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

AllAfrica is committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of those who use allAfrica.com. This statement outlines how we handle any personal information we obtain.

From time to time, we may ask for data that identifies you, as in user surveys or orders placed through our site. We use this information to operate this site, provide you with the highest quality services and offer you opportunities we think will be of interest.

You also may choose to provide information about yourself by participating in various forums we intend to offer for readers. You should remember that when you yourself voluntarily disclose personal information to other Internet users, such as when you include personal information in a posting to an online discussion forum, that information could be used by others and may result in unsolicited messages or other forms of attention.

AllAfrica uses IP addresses to analyze traffic and administer this site. IP addresses track individual computers and do not contain personally identifiable data. In order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and others, we may disclose user information, but only in a form that does not identify individuals. For example, we might disclose that a certain percentage of our users are female or within a certain age range.

## E-Commerce

When allAfrica.com offers items for sale, information is collected to process the orders and is used only in relation to that transaction. It is not sold to other vendors. We also host or provide links to advertisers, sponsors and online stores that sell a variety of goods and services. These vendors may ask you for information, such as your name and credit card number. AllAfrica does _not_ collect, use or disclose this information, nor does it own or control the vendors or have responsibility for transactions made by those merchants. If you would like to know more about the information collected when you participate in e-commerce through this site, please contact the merchants directly.

## Cookies

A "cookie" is a small data text file that can be placed in your browser to enable a server to recognize you each time you visit this site. Cookies are necessary for this and other sites to provide individualized services, such as subscriptions. 

Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, nor does AllAfrica use cookies to collect personal information. In addition to recognizing subscribers, our cookies may sometimes be used to track which parts of our site you have used so that we can better serve you when you return. Advertisers may use cookies to determine or control how many times you see their message or to customize the message you are presented.

## Email

AllAfrica will _never_ give your email address to anyone else. We will only send you mail in response to your questions, as follow-up to your transactions, or as part of services for which you have signed up.

## Third Party Ad Serving and Sites

AllAfrica works with carefully chosen third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [_visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) opt-out page_](http://networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

The [_DoubleClick DART cookie_](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) is used by Google in ads served on this site and other websites displaying AdSense ads. When users visit an AdSense publisher's website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user's browser. The data gathered from these cookies will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [_Google ad and content network privacy policy._](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

_[Advertising.com](http://www.platform-a.com/advertiser-solutions)_ collects what is known as "Click Stream Data," which is anonymous and includes a web user's IP address, web pages viewed, date and time of access and responses by a web surfer to an advertisement.

For more information about the companies whose ads appear on this site, read the privacy statements for [_advertising.com_](http://www.platform-a.com/privacy-policy/advertisingcom), [_Google_](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html), [_Casale Media_](http://casalemedia.com/privacy.html), [_Value Click_](https://www.valueclickmedia.com/privacy.shtml), [_Tribal Fusion_](http://www.tribalfusion.com/TribalFusion/privacy.html) and [_Tacoda_](http://www.platform-a.com/advertiser-solutions/audience-targeting/behavioral-targeting).

Some of our pages contain links to other sites that may have information practices different from ours. AllAfrica has no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. You should consult the privacy notices of any site you choose to visit.

## Disclosing Information to Others

AllAfrica will only disclose personal information when required to do so by law or when we have your explicit permission to do so.
